

JUNIOR AT RENSSELAER POLYTECHNIC INSTITUT

Greater Boston Area, MA

■ nguyenjason06@gmail.com | 😭 dangitjason.github.io | 🖸 DangItJason | 🛅 jnguyen576

Summary_

Technical leader who loves empowering a team to turn ideas into a reality. Part-time nerd who uses coding as a tool to solve personal problems. Ready to utilize learned technical skills, academic background and leadership in a professional experience to contribute to a greater-cause.

Skills

Languages: (proficient) Python (familiar): C/C++, Java, Javascript (+ES6)

Technologies: Linux, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB (Mongoose), HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Git, npm

Education

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Trov, NY

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, 3.52 GPA

Expected Graduation: May 2022

Dean's Honor List: Fall 18', Spring 19'

Experience

RCOS Troy, NY

Developer and Project Lead May. 2020 - Present

- Leading a team of 5 developers to create a platform that connects campus students to tutors and provides tutors a business management tool.
- Wrote a software requirement specification to identify project scope, requirements, goals and high level design.
- Used React.js framework and Bootstrap to develop clean, functional user dashboards.
- Created RESTful API endpoints using Node.js and Express.js frameworks to communicate with a NoSQL database.
- Follows MVC design pattern for simultaneous development, cohesion and performance.

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Science Department

Troy, NY

Undergraduate Computer Science Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- · Guided new computer science students to build and develop proper programming practices during lab periods.
- Directly influenced growth of 30+ students through instructing with Python programming exercises.

Projects

You can view each project at dangitjason.github.io

Multi-threaded Chat Server

C, LINUX, SOCKET PROGRAMMING Aug. 2020

· Developed a multi-threaded chat server in C that allows communication between connected clients over TCP and UDP connections.

A* Path Finding Algorithm Visualization

PYTHON, TKINTER May. 2020

- Developed a python script that uses A* search algorithm to find the lowest cost path from start to end destinations.
- Uses Tkinter Python module to visualize the algorithm's decisions and add obstacles to grid.

Login and SignUp System

JS ES6, BOOTSTRAP CSS, NODE.JS, EXPRESS.JS, REACT.JS, MONGODB, NPM

Apr. 2020 - May. 2020

- Developed a functional login and sign-up page for a full-stack fitness application.
- Uses React.js framework and Bootstrap CSS for front-end UI.
- Created RESTful API endpoints using Node.js and Express.js to support CRUD operations.

GroupMe Chat Bot

PYTHON, GOOGLE CALENDER API

- Developed a chat bot using Python to inform and remind group members of weekly upcoming events.
- Retrieved, stored and pushed important dates through Google Calendar API.